Euan McKay – Resume

3D Artist & Software Developer

Personal Summary:

Hi, I'm Euan. Over the past decade I've watched a curiosity in programming transform into a 1st class Honours degree in computer science, and feeling a passing curiosity in 3D art transform into a desire to carve a name for myself in the industry. Really, Its just a dream to flex my creative muscles and make things people will love: whether its problem solving my way through programming challenges, or getting to be a part of an artistic project that captures peoples imagination.

To be honest, I started creating 3D art for 'Planetside 2' because I didn't like any of the cosmetics available at the time. However, ever since I started seeing people get excited over my work, it lit a spark in me; fuelling my desire to not just make things for me, but to make things that people love.

Qualifications:

Heriot-Watt University – BSC Computer Science – Edinburgh (2018):

Honours: Graduated with 1st class honours; winner of the Walker-Cooper prize; Winner of the deputy principals prize.

Dissertation: I was awarded an A grade and the Walker-Cooper prize for my dissertation on procedural level generation. The finished dissertation successfully produced a configurable tool in Unity & C# which would produce procedural levels and functional mini-maps given a set of tiles. <u>Link to Dissertation report.</u>

Notable Courses:

- 3rd Year Project:: I received an A grade for my group project in my 3rd year. This project revolved around producing a resource allocation system for IT companies. The produced system allowed the user to organize staff by using a web based application with server side functionality. For the system the group also produced a marketing website, robust back end and full documentation.
- 3D Graphics Course: In my final year I tool a comprehensive graphics course which taught me how to create and implement a graphics pipeline, shaders and rendering engine using openGL and C++.
- Other courses taken: Discrete Maths, Games Programming, Data Mining, Big Data, Web Design, Al and Language Processing.

Skills:

Programming Languages:

C, C#,C++, Python, Java, JavaScript, SML, openGL, PDDL.

Web & Database Development:

HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, SQL

Graphics Technologies:

Maya, Blender, Substance Painter, Substance Designer, Zbrush, Photoshop, Marvellous Designer, Marmoset Toolbag, Unity, Unreal Engine.

Experience:

DayBreak Games (2015 – present)

Contract Artist - Planetside 2:

- Worked with the producer and art department to create a set of cosmetic items for 'Planetside 2'. These Items were shipped on-time and up to standard.
- The created cosmetic Items were developed for an upcoming faction, and had to meet both aesthetic and technical qualities.

FreeLance Artist - Planetside 2:

• Produced over 50 cosmetic items for sale in the cash shop of 'Planetside 2'. These items had to both meet the games strict technical requirements, as well as having to fit the games aesthetic and meet the art directors standards. Items created include helmets, aircraft, full characters and vehicles.

- Helped expand the categories of the cash shop in 'Planetside 2' by opening up successful categories such as 'aircraft cosmetics' to their 'PlayerStudio' program.
- Helped budding freelance artists within the 'PlayerStudio' program with learning 3D modelling and texturing. From Q&A, live streams or producing tutorial videos.
- Worked on commission for players to produce custom content for 'Planetside 2'.
- Used proprietary tools to prepare cosmetic items for the game.

St Cecilias Hall (2019)

Application Developer:

- Worked with the museum directors and masters students to produce an application for the museum.
- The application is a web-based interface which would allow users to play audio clips guiding users around the museums collection, as well as playing audio clips from the museums instruments.

Edinburgh Business Weekend (2016-2017)

Senior Technology and Web Manager:

- Met regularly with the president of the Edinburgh business weekend (EBW) to update and revamp their website, and manage the online applications and processing for the 2016 and 2017 EBW events.
- Maintained the EBW website and helped streamline and clear up websites source files.

Global Game Jam 2019: Heriot Watt Team (2019)

Artist and Level Designer:

- Worked with a university team to compete in 2019s global game jam.
- Over the course of 48 hours I produced a wide range of props and characters for my teams entry in the jam, and
 was responsible for a large section of as well as working on rigging and assisting other team members with
 programming.

NoSense Games (2018-present)

Lead Artist, level designer and programmer – MechaMania:

- Over the past year I have been working with a fellow computer science graduate to develop our own game.
- Despite getting off to a slow start we have been making steady strides working on it on weekends, and are now well into early beta, with an official announcement and open beta planned for the summer.
- In this project I have been in charge of shaping the art style and producing assets; programming weapons and UI, developing gameplay loops and refining code.
- The work has posed many technical (developing a character system that both is physics based and network-compatible) and artistic challenges (from character identification, performance constraints to building a brand), however we are taking strides daily to overcome these.

Contact:

Email: EuanEdwardMcKay@Gmail.com Portfolio website: McKay3d.co.uk

 $Linked In: \underline{https://www.linkedin.com/in/euan-mckay-8962a3128/}$

Artstation: https://www.artstation.com/euanmckay